When we're thinking about a simple vending machine it's easy to enumerate the states.
単純な自動販売機について考えるときには 状態を列挙するのは簡単です
Now let's consider the states we may want to model for car driving on a highway.
今度は高速道路を走行している車をモデル化するために必要な状態を考えてみましょう
Benny, let's just throw out all the ideas we can come up with and then prune the list
思いつくように考えていく方法を紹介できるように
afterwards so we can show how we might think about
思いついたアイデアをすべて言っていき
coming up with a finite state machine from scratch.
後でリストを削っていこう
Okay, let's keep it simple first.
了解 まずは単純になるようにしよう
What happens if we are the only car on the road?
道路には自分たちの車しかいない場合はどうだろう?
I guess we would need a state for normal staying in your lane driving.
走行している車線に普通に留まっている状態が必要だと思う
If we are changing lanes,
車線を変える場合
we want a state to represent that.
それを表す状態が必要になる
Or maybe two states since changing lanes to the left is different than to the right.
左への車線変更は右へのものとは違うので 2 つの状態がいるかも
Okay. I guess. What changes if there's a vehicle in front of us?
うんたぶん自分たちの前に車両があった場合何が変わる?
Well we might want to stay behind it,
その後ろにいたいだろうから
so we should have a state for that or we might want to pass it.
そのための状態が必要で もしくはその車を抜かしたいかもしれない
I suppose, but isn't
そうだね でも追い越しは左へ車線変更してから
pass just a lane change to the left and then a lane change to the right?
右へ車線変更することだけじゃない?
Do we really need in your state for that?
本当にそれ用の状態に必要かな?
Hey, we're brainstorming no bad ideas.
ブレーンストーミングしているんだから悪いアイデアではないよ
Okay, fine. Well, what changes if we had more cars?
そうかじゃあ もっと車があったらどう変わるだろうか?
I could imagine in this situation you might want to slow down so that you
その状況ではこの隙間に入れるよう速度を落として
could merge into this gap here and then pass this car if it's going slow.
この車が遅かったら追い越したくなると思う
We should really have a slow downstate
速度を落とす状態がほんとに必要で
which I guess means we will also need a speed upstate.
そうしたら加速の状態も必要になるだろう
We should probably add a stop state in case there is some emergency situation.
緊急事態があった場合の停止状態もきっと追加しないと
I guess we could do all of that at once by having a keep target speed state.
ターゲットの速度を維持する状態を用意すると 一度にそのすべてをできるかもしれない
Well I don't know.
うーん どうだろう
Shouldn't speed just be dictated by the lane you're driving in and the speed limit?
スピードだけが走行している車線と速度制限によって決められるべきではないよね?
What if we just add a prepare lane change state to represent when
自車が車線変更の前に 通行車の隙間の横に進もうとしているとき
the ego vehicle is trying to go next to an empty gap in traffic before a lane change?
を表す 車線変更準備状態を追加したらどうかな
Yeah, that could work but we should probably have
それはうまくいくかもしれないけど たぶん
a prepare lane change left and to prepare a lane change right,
車線変更左準備と車線変更右準備が必要になる
since those really are different maneuvers.
これらはだいぶ違った操作だから
Oh, and we could also turn on the turn signals down.
あ それから方向指示器をつけないと
Good point. The truth is there isn't a single correct set of states to choose from.
たしかに実は選び出す状態の正しいセットは 1 つではありません
On one hand we want to keep our state space as small as
保守性の面で状態空間をできるだけ小さく
possible for maintainability reasons,
維持する一方で 気に掛けるすべての物理的状態を
but on the other hand we want to make sure we have enough logical States
実際に表すために十分論理的な
to actually represent all the physical states that we care about.
状態を確保したいのです
As you've seen in the discussion we've just had it's
このディスカッションからわかるように このシナリオに対して
not easy to find the perfect set of states for this scenario.
完璧な状態のセットを見つけることは簡単ではありません
Why don't you think for a minute about what states you would want
少し時間をかけて 高速道路での車両の行動を表すのに
to use to represent vehicle behavior on a highway.
使用したい状態について考えてみてください
Check the boxes next to each state that you'd keep and
採用する各状態の横のチェックボックスをオンにして
write any additional ones in the empty boxes on the left.
追加したいものがあれば左側の空欄に書き留めてください